Ethan J. Reimer

ereimer18@georgefox.edu | (253) 709-0006 | linkedin.com/in/ethan-reimer-0487a9178 | github.com/ereimer18

Professional Summary

Highly motivated computer science major with a focus in cyber security. A devoted team member with leadership skills, dedication and experience working with a variety of groups and cultures. Able to diligently perform a wide variety of tasks with key organizational skills and close attention to detail. Curious with a strong desire to learn and take on projects offering new skills.

Education

George Fox University, Newberg, OR

Expected April 2022

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Cyber Security | GPA: 3.64

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures, Digital Logic, Software Engineering, Discrete Mathematics, Computer Security and Digital Forensics, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Analysis of Algorithms, Emerging Mobile Technologies, Database Systems, Data Communications and Networks, Computer Architecture/Assembly Languages, Servant Engineering I, Operating Systems, Network Administration, Secure Software, Servant Engineering II

Technical Skills

- Java
- Python
- JUnit Testing
- Git
- C/C++
- Scala

- SQL
- PostgreSQL
- Version Control
- Linux
- Virtual Machines
- UML

- Object-Oriented Programming
- E-R Diagrams
- Data Structures
- IP Subnetting
- Java Multithreading

Professional Experience

Groundskeeper, LifeWay Church, Federal Way, WA

Dec 2020-Jan 2021

- Assisted the church staff to prepare for events to better reach the community.
- Installed several new camera systems to improve livestreaming capabilities.
- General maintenance and organization of the church property.

Retail Associate, Lowes, Federal Way, WA

June 2020-Aug 2020

- Worked in the Lumber and Building Materials department to provide helpful customer service.
- Assisted customers in finding merchandise, answering questions, and loading heavy items.
- Aimed to improve and maintain the organization of my department and the availability of products.

Amazon Warehouse Associate, Amazon, Kent, WA

May 2019-July 2019

• Stocked and distributed items as a water-strider working with my team to provide optimal product availability to customers.

Gig Musician, Various Ensembles, Tacoma WA and Newberg OR

Summer 2017-Spring 2019

<u>Collegiate Projects</u> (view at https://portfolium.com/EthanReimer)

- Chess Program: applied O-O programming techniques to program a command-line driven chess game.
- Servant Engineering Haptic Feedback Device: working with my team to create a haptic feedback device to aid visually impaired students in understanding a graphical image. My particular focus has been creating a microfluidic chip with an inflating diaphragm and developing a color tracking program utilizing computer vision.
- Capitol Breach Incident Response Plan: researched and formulated an emergency cybersecurity incident response plan following the January 6th, 2021 breach of the Capitol.
- Magic Mirror IoT Device: worked with my partner to program, configure and build a "magic mirror" smart device, consisting of a pi-driven monitor behind a two-way mirror that displayed modules such as the weather and notifications.
- Movie Database: working with my team, we parsed old HTML and XML files and created a
 PostgreSQL movie database that held data including movies, actors, awards, studios, directors and
 more.
- **Networking RFP:** drafted a bid in response to a hypothetical business Request for Proposal in my Data Communications and Networking course. Researched networking equipment and protocols necessary and put together a plan to restore a company to working order and improve network setup.

Contests

National Cyber League, Spring 2021

Volunteer Experience

Bryansk, Russia: served alongside local church leaders and international workers to better reach the needs of the community during the summers of 2016 through 2018. Self-taught basic conversational language skills during and after my time on the field.

ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest, 2018: volunteered to help run the Oregon ACM ICPC hosted by George Fox University.

Leadership Experience

Principal Cellist, Stadium High School Chamber Orchestra

2017-2018

Co-Principal Cellist, George Fox University Symphony

2018-2019